RG 060, Commission to Make Repairs to Capitol and to Procure Site for New Building for State Officials
Connecticut State Library
Commission to Make Repairs to Capitol and to Procure Site for New Building for State Officials records
1904-1914
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Commission to Make Repairs to Capitol and to Procure Site for New Building for State Officials
5.5 cubic feet
The Commission was established by the General Assembly in 1903 to make repairs to the State Capitol and to “investigate and ascertain the necessity of erecting an additional building.”
RG060
T002728
Historical Note
The Commission was established by the General Assembly in 1903 to make repairs to the State Capitol and to “investigate and ascertain the necessity of erecting an additional building.” Governor Abiram Chamberlain appointed Morgan G. Bulkeley, H. Wales Lines, Charles C. Cook, W.O. Burr, and L. W. Robinson to the five-member commission. In 1905, the Commission was asked to purchase land, to procure plans and specifications for a new State Library and Supreme Court building, and obtain bids for its construction. Soon thereafter the Comptroller was added to the commission as an ex officio member and the commission embarked on securing land and contracting for and fully complete and furnish a building to be used by the State Library, Supreme Court and Memorial Hall. Secretary Robinson and Treasurer Cook were chosen as the Building Committee that was responsible for the construction of the State Library and Supreme Court Building. Samuel O. Prentice, Judge of the Supreme Court, and State Librarian George S. Godard consulted with the commission during the planning and construction of the building designed by Donn Barber, architect. The building opened on November 28, 1910, the day after Thanksgiving and on the anniversary of Godard's appointment.
Scope and Content
Records include correspondence, meeting minutes, arbitration agreements and contracts, financial records, and photographs documenting the construction of the new State Library and Supreme Court Building
Related Material
Classified Archives:
727.8 C761d, Detailed plans, elevations and specifications... by Donn Barber, architect, 7 oversized volumes.
727.8 C761p, Floor plans of the State Library and Supreme Court building, by Donn Barber, architect 1 oversize volume.
727.8 C761p supp, Loose correspondence, contracts, etc.
PG 220, Connecticut State Library Collection.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Commission to Make Repairs to Capitol and to Procure Site for New Building for State Officials; Connecticut. Commission to Make Repairs to Capitol and Erect a State Library and Supreme Court Building
Persons:
Barber, Donn, b. 1871
Subjects:
Connecticut. Commission to Make Repairs to Capitol and to Procure Site for New Building for State Officials -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut. Commission to Make Repairs to Capitol and Erect a State Library and Supreme Court Building -- Records and correspondence; State libraries -- Connecticut -- Hartford -- Design and construction
Document Types:
Contracts; Correspondence; Financial records; Memorandums; Minutes; Photographs; Programs
Restrictions on Access
Construction Photographs
In 2005 and 2006, the State Archives funded a project to make 8 X 10 prints of the construction photographs so that the originals could be retired from use. In addition, the State Archives obtained b&w negatives of the original shots so that duplicates could be made. Photograph boxes 1 and 2 of the originals are restricted as is box 5 that contains the negatives. Box 6 that contains the use copies may be used by researchers. Boxes 3 and 4 contain original photographs that were not duplicated because they do not show the building under construction. Only these originals may be used by researchers.
Some of these records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1904-1914
  - 1. Incoming correspondence (Box 1)
    - R. Boker (Box 1)
    - Morgan G. Bulkeley (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - H. Wales Lines (Box 1)
    - Edward T. Hapgood (Box 1)
    - Donn Barber (Box 1)
    - Charles C. Cook (Box 1)
    - L.W. Robinson, 24 folders (Box 1)
      Alphabetical by correspondent.
    - George S. Godard to Charles C. Cook (Box 1)
    - George S. Godard to L.W. Robinson (Box 1)
    - George S. Godard, Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - 2. Outgoing correspondence (Box 2)
    Contains the following, not necessarily in the order listed.
    - Robinson to various contractors (Box 2)
      Arranged in alphabetical order.
    - Robinson to Morgan G. Bulkeley (Box 2)
    - Specifications, estimates and bids (Box 2)
    - Contracts and agreements (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Lots grading-curbing and sidewalks (Box 2)
    - Meetings minutes and votes (Box 2)
    - Granite (Box 2)
    - Insurance (Box 2)
    - Power-heat-light (Box 2)
    - Drinking water system (Box 2)
  - 3. Records, 1904-1914; 3 volumes (Box 3)
    Includes minutes of meetings, memoranda, copies of Correspondence.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Pages 1-301, 1904 June 15-1909 May 25 (Volume Volume 1)
    - Unpaginated memorandum, 1909 July 1 (Volume Volume 1)
    - Pages 302-596, 1909-May 29-1910 October 25 (Volume Volume 2)
    - Pages 597-820, 1910 September 10-1914 February 10 (Volume Volume 3)
    - Unpaginated statements, correspondence, receipts, 1908 October 14-1914 February 25 (Volume Volume 3)
      Not in chronological order.
  - 4. Correspondence and miscellaneous notes, 1909-1913; Two folders in a large envelope. (Box 3)
    Generally arranged chronologically.
  - 5. Arbitration agreements and contracts, 1911-1913; One large envelope (Box 3)
    No arrangement.
  - 6. Checkbook and bank account book, 1909 (Box 3)
    Account book with the National New Haven Bank kept by Commission Secretary L. W. Robinson.
  - 7. Copies of program of ceremonies attending the laying of the corner stone Tuesday, May 25, 1909 (Box 3)
  - 8. Photo albums of construction of the State Library and Supreme Court Building, 1908-1910
    Taken out of albums in the fall, 1988.
    - Construction photographs
      Box 6 contains use copies of restricted originals in boxes 1 and 2. Box 1 contains originals for numbers 1-32 and box 2 contains originals for numbers 33-66 listed below.
      - 1. Foundation facing southeast, Library and Memorial Hall, 1908; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 2. Foundation facing east, 1908; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 3. Foundation facing east, 1908 December 5; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 4. Foundation facing east, 1908 December 5; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 5. Foundation, 1908 December 9; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 6. Front from Capitol, 1908 December 9; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 7. Foundation from Capitol, 1908; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 8. Foundation facing northwest, 1908; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 9. Foundation, 1909 January 7; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 10. Front from Capitol, 1909, January 7; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 11. Front from Capitol, 1909 January 22; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 12. Foundation facing south (forman), 1909 January 22; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 13. Foundation, 1909 February 5; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 14. Front from Capitol, 1909 February 5; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 15. Foundation, 1909 February 23; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 16. Front from Capitol, 1909 February 23; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 17. Foundation facing north, 1909 March 10; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 18. Front from Capitol, 1909 March 10; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 19. Facing west, 1909 March 26; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 20. Front from Capitol, 1909 March 26; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 21. Scaffolding facing west, 1909 April 10; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 22. Front from Capitol, 1909 April 10; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 23. Scaffolding facing north, 1909 April 26; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 24. Front from Capitol, 1909 April 26; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 25. Scaffolding facing north, 1909 May 10; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 26. Front from Capitol, 1909 May 10; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 27. Scaffolding facing north, 1909 May 24; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 28. Front from Capitol, 1909 May 24; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 29. Scaffolding facing east, 1909 June 6; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 30. Front from Capitol, 1909 June 6; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 31. Facing east, 1909 June 23; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 32. Front from Capitol, 1909 June 23; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 33. Top facing east, 1909 July 7; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 34. Front from Capitol, 1909 July 7; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 35. Top facing east, 1909 July 21; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 36. Front from Capitol, 1909 July 21; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 37. Top facing east, 1909 August 4; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 38. Front from Capitol, 1909 August 4; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 39. Top facing east, 1909 August 18; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 40. Front from Capitol, 1909 August 18; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 41. Roof facing southeast, 1909 September 1; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 42. Front from Capitol, 1909 September 1; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 43. Roof facing east, 1909 September 15; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 44. Front from Capitol, 1909 September 15; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 45. Roof facing east, 1909 September 29; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 46. Front from Capitol, 1909 September 29; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 47. Roof facing east, 1909 October 13; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 48. Front from Capitol, 1909 October 13; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 49. Roof facing east, 1909 October 27; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 50. Front from Capitol, 1909 October 27; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 51. Roof facing east, 1909 November 10; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 52. Front from Capitol, 1909 November 10; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 53. Roof facing east with snow, 1909 November 24; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 54. No picture - missing (Box 6)
      - 55. Roof facing east, 1909 December 8; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 56. Front from Capitol, 1909 December 8; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 57. Southside (library side), 1909 December 22; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 58. Front from Capitol, 1909 December 22; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 59. Front from Capitol with snow, 1909 December; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 60. No picture - missing (Box 6)
      - 61. East side, 1910 January 19; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 62. Front from Capitol in snow, 1910 January 19; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 63. Front from west, 1910 February 2; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 64. Front from Capitol, 1910 February 2; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 65. Front from Capitol in snow, circa 1909-1910; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
      - 66. Southside (court side), circa 1909-1910; b&w, 8 x 10 in. (Box 6)
    - Interior and Exterior views
      These are original photographs that were not duplicated because they do not show construction.
      - Floor of museum, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Ceiling to Supreme Court room, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Supreme Court, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Statuary "Art", circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Statuary "Art" side view (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Statuary "Art" side vieww (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Statuary "Science" front of library (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Statuary "Science" (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Statuary "Science" side view (3), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Statuary "Justice" (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Statuary "Justice" (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Statuary "Justice" side view (3), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Statuary "History" (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Statuary "History" (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Statuary "History" side view (3), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - North view with snow, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Northeast view with snow, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Left half of building north view, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - North view with man in front, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Northeast view, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - East view of front, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Slight northeast view with man in front, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - East view of front, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - North view left side of building, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Northeast view, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - East view (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - East view (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 3)
      - Main reading room, Law (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Main reading room, Law (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Main reading room, Stacks (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Main reading room, Stacks (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Stacks (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Stacks (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Supreme Court room (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Supreme Court room (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Supreme Court room (3), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Supreme Court room (4), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Supreme Court room, back of room, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Ceiling of the Supreme Court, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Main foyer (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Main foyer (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Main foyer (3), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Main foyer (4), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Memorial Hall Museum (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Memorial Hall Museum (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Memorial Hall Museum (3), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Museum, Washington photo, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Front from Capitol (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Front from Capitol (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Front from Capitol (3), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Front from Capitol (4), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Front from Capitol (5), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Front from Capitol (6), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Front from Capitol (7), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Eastside of building (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Eastside of building (2), b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Front of building from the east side, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Northeast photo (1), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Northeast photo (2), circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Front with statuary, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Statuary, "Justice" and "History", circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Close up of statuary "Justice" and "History", circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Far shot of statuary "Justice" and "History", circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)
      - Northeast view with statuary, circa 1910-1911; b&w, 11 x 14 in. (Box 4)